<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Aidenkrz <aiden@djkraz.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Chief-Engineer <119664036+Chief-Engineer@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Kira Gbedan <161087999+Verbalase@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Piras314 <92357316+Piras314@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 basic pack <159909786+packmore@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <aiden@djkraz.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Intro
**Welcome to Ratbite, we do things a little differently (less lame) than most Space Station 14 servers currently available so you should read our rules more than you would most servers.
Quick notes:
Most of our rules are handled with permanent brig sentences, the ones that you ABSOLUTELY MUST follow are listed below and Multi Round perma sentence details are found in the legal SoP section of guidebook.

We expect our users to be and act 16+

This is NOT NRP or a "self antag server." We encourage you to do unique bits and RP shit out, be aware of things like self antag and type baiting being ALLOWED. (though heavily nerfed)

Before we begin for the short attention spanned users among us, if you are MINDSHIELDED, you follow more rules and should read the full list, so read in full.**

# Hard adminnable rules EVERYONE must follow

## 1A. This isn't Goob or Wizden.
Abandon your preconceptions from other servers. You are free to do whatever you want here, but with in-game consequences. The only exceptions are the rest of these basic rules. We encourage you to handle situations in a way you would  in reality instead of waiting for divine intervention even in the presence of rule breakers, call security, fight, use the buffed shove, run, THEN report if need be, don't be a looc keyboard warrior.

## 2A. The obvious rules, do not engage sexually or be a bigoted PoS
While we allow for ingame specism/mild racism and jokes/insults that may reference concepts such as sexuality, race, or other rude to mention things. We draw a sharp line at actual OOC racism, bigotry in general, or degenerative ideologies promoting said concepts. We also draw a sharp line at any and all sex talk, fetish talk, and other things that could potentially harm the minds of folk on this minor accessible server.
You are allowed to do romance RP or "E-Date" in a non explicit fashion (stop at non descriptive kissing and "I love you"s) ONLY UNDER THE CONDITION that you know this person outside the game. You do NOT know how old any one player is, nor do you know how these kinds of relations would affect their mental state, also, have some self respect.

## 3A. Play your character, No ghost grudging
You are expected to play a character and not reference game mechanics directly. Almost every server has this rule. Do not refer to the admins, stuff you're doing in real life, game controls, and other out of universe concepts directly. You may use LOOC or obfuscate these things as in universe concepts however. (E.G admins=gods/centcomm, right click=shove, going AFK=suffering from SSD)

DO NOT use ghost roles/respawns to get revenge or punish specific players. RP the new character. On YOUR character however, You may remember past rounds (even if you died, you are a mental clone of your previous in this case), so general resentment and metagrudge from past rounds is permitted to keep everyone feeling the social consequences of their actions, but DO NOT use knowledge from your previous life/death during the current round to meta-grudge and impact the round unless directed to by an Ahelp message.

## 4A. Local metacomm allowed, unfair metacomm info sharing is not.
Do NOT expose game info you should not know via meta-communications. (discord or other voice chat applications) You may play with friends and share basic information in close proximity within reason, just explain it as being really in tune with your buddy through eyebrow waggling or some psychic link or whatever, but DO NOT speak to your pal from the dead or give vital info over vast distances. You may tell your pal to check their radio if they miss your words.

## 5A. No hacked clients, ban evasion, or brigading the server.
While we allow a great many more antagonistic behaviors and are overall one of the most based servers currently available for space station 14, some more degenerative internet users (often referred to as "raiders") seek to undermine and abuse even the place that would most readily welcome them with the most minor of adjustments to their behavior, they use largely untraceable alternative accounts and cheating software.

The admins are given explicit license to instantly ban you if they suspect you of being one of these people, if you get banned as a false positive because you just enjoy being antagonistic as a new ratbite player, appeal it on discord and it will be removed ASAP!

Ban evasion extends to the multi round brig system, serve your sentence in good faith.

## 6A. Follow borg laws/mind control.
Silicons must follow their laws. Similarly, characters who are mind controlled or under similar effects that dictate their behaviour must obey their master and/or laws. Failure to comply will result in your character being treated as defective (possibly exploding) and your maker/master will be compensated for their loss.
This also applies to team and team conversion antags such as cults and revolutionaries, do not intentionally work against your team antagonists without VERY good IC reason. If unsure ask Ahelp.

## 7A. Speak primarily English (Ahelp for exception)
We understand there's a great many interesting and fun things to be done with language gags, but if you wish to communicate in an entirely different language, just ahelp and ask to. Speaking a different language very temporarily to prove a point or make a joke is of course fine.

## 8A. Respect the first 15 minutes grace.
Everyone (except for antagonists with objectives permitting) must act as if they were mindshielded (as seen in rule 2B below) for the first 15 minutes. A note is that if you are a known threat to the station, people ARE permitted to grudge you/try to apprehend you within reason, and should this be the case, you are allowed to defend yourself within reason.
(This rule exists because it would take a Godly amount of design work and consistently great secoffs to deal with roundstart rushing of power items through violence. I hope to phase this rule out in time as it DOES go against my game design over rules philosophy, but for now it stands as a necessary evil to cover up the holes I have yet to fix in wizden/goob's design.)

## 9A. Be helpful in Ahelp, do not abuse Ahelp.
You are expected to be forward and truthful with admins in Ahelp. If you willfully lie to admins in Ahelp or withhold information you can and will catch a ban.
Admins are permitted you give you a one hour ban at their discretion if you are disruptive via mass spam or abusive conduct in Ahelp.

</Document>
