<Document>
# High Command SOP
This is the list of expectations and authorities granted to [color=#1b67a5][bold]High Command[/bold][/color] on board this station.

--- This is the chain of command for [color=#1b67a5][bold]Central Command[/bold][/color]

Centcomm Director/Sector Governor

Centcomm Official (CCO)

-Above explicitly DO NOT have bomb implants

Centcom Intern

Navy Captain/Special Operations Officer

-Above are High Command

-Below are delegates with termination bomb implants

Navy Officer

Death Squad Operative (DSO)

ERT/HECU

Nanotrasen Representative/Redsight Overseer

---

1. As per the foremost directive of most lesser Central Command staff, they are to obey and comply with the orders of Central Command above all other directives. “Central Command” is considered to be any Centcomm Official equal in rank to CCO or higher. They may be remotely detonated at your discretion if even mildly disobedient, but misuse of this, as you know, will likely result in dismissal from our ranks.
<Box>Abuses of this power, or any other power granted by this set of expectations are handled internally. If a CCO or higher is acting awry you should submit a report about them ASAP and this misuse of their privileged position will be addressed internally. (Ahelp it or submit a report if its so bad it hurts the RP, these are admins and can be demoted for being outright unfun.) </Box>




2. Navy Captain, Special Operations Officer, and higher are considered to be above all of space law and other central command SoP, though abuses of this power (that which do not serve NT’s interests) will result in internal dismissal of these officers.




3. Disobeying a Centcomm Official or higher is considered a capital offense that can result in demotion, permanent brigging, or on the spot execution at the behest of and only if deemed necessary by the CCO that delivered the order. Any lesser punishment or abuse is to be considered a mercy.




4. Centcomm Officials and higher are expected (but not outright required) to STAY OUT of most conflict driven by rival corporate entities or esoteric beings (antagonists). A CCO CANNOT be deployed to every single station in every single situation, and their combat proficiency varies WILDLY. Thusly it is deemed better by our Sector Governor that they observe and report so that we may better prepare our baseline station security. Though seeing that their direct orders are carried out when a delegate fails to do so or handling more common and domestic problems/misconduct is expected and encouraged to normalize NT compliant behaviors.




5. Centcomm Interns are ordered (by CCO authority) to listen to and obey anyone who had called them in them via drop pod through the NTR standard executive briefcase. Should an NTR be in the vicinity, the interns are to report to them instead. Should the NTR and whoever called the interns fall, they are beholden to the captain/acting captain’s orders. In the event there is no captain or valid candidate for acting captain, they may assume captaincy.






</Document>
